Register of the Paul Robert Hanna Papers, 1920-1997
Hoover Institution Archives
- INCREMENT OF NOVEMBER 1985
  - Stanford University
    - School of Education
      - Ten dissertations resulting from research project for elementary social studies, September 1959 (Folder 206: 3)
  - Trips
    - 1962-66 (Folder 206: 4)
    - 1963-68 (Folder 206: 5)
  - Warner, Rollin M.
    - "Africa, Asia, Russia,", 1976 (Folder 206: 6)
    - "The Individual and the Corporation,", 1975 (Folder 206: 7)
  - Wittlin, Alma S. (central nervous system) (Folder 206: 8)
  - World Book Encyclopedia
    - General (Folder 206: 9)
    - Meetings
      - 1958-1963 (Folder 206: 10)
      - April 22-24, 1965 (Box-folder 207: 1)
  - Writings by Paul Hanna with others
    - General (Folder 207: 2)
    - "Content in the Social Studies: Generalizations From the Social Sciences,", 1962. (Folder 207: 3)
    - "Curriculum Innovations for th State's Quality Growth As We Approach 2000 AD,", October 31, 1966. (Folder 207: 4)
    - "The Peace Corps and the University," Washington, D.C., April 1969. (Folder 207: 5)
    - Report of the Binational Advisory Commission for Long-Term Cooperation Between the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia and the United States of America, December 2, 1966. (Folder 207: 6)
    - "Spelling: Structure and Strategies," with Jean Hanna and Richard Hodges, 1969. (Folder 207: 7-8)
  - "Youth Serves the Community" projects, 1936-37. (Folder 207: 9)
  - Miscellany (Folder 207: 10)
  - Printed matter
  - Printed matter (Box 208)
- INCREMENT OF NOVEMBER 1985
  - Organizations, 1967-1986
    - Associates of the Libraries, 1984 (Folder 209: 1)
      Announcement, brochures, correspondence, lists of appointees, memoranda, minutes of Board of Director's meeting, report, and schedules
    - Imprint - Library Associates, 1983-1984. (Folder 209: 2)
      Memoranda, remarks by Richard E. Hodges, and report
    - Associates - General correspondence, 1983 (Folder 209: 3)
      Includes announcements, annual report, brochure, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and remarks
    - Associates of Stanford University Libraries - By-laws work papers, 1982 (Folder 209: 4)
      Includes minutes of meetings
    - Associates - Stanford Libraries, 1982 (Folder 209: 5)
      General correspondence. Includes brochures, clippings, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, report by John Y. Cole, and roster of committees
    - Associates of Stanford University Libraries, Tenth anniversary celebration, 1983 (Folder 209: 6)
      Includes articles by Paul R. Hanna, clippings, correspondence, draft outline of an Imprint article, memoranda, and report
    - Pending, Associates trip to Japan - Work file, 1983 (Folder 209: 7)
      Includes correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meeting, report, and schedule
    - Associates - Stanford Libraries, 1967-1981 (Folder 210: 1)
      Research worksheet and related materials
    - Associates - Stanford Libraries, 1981 (Folder 210: 2)
      Brochures, clippings, correspondence, list of members of Board of Directors, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletter, notes, and remarks
    - Associates of the Library - Imprint, 1981-1983 (Folder 210: 3-4)
      Includes articles, correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and personal notes
    - Bohemian Club - General, 1981-1985 (Folder 210: 5-6)
      Alphabetical roster of members, officers, and committees, brochures, correspondence, form letter, list of members of camp supervisors, memoranda, newsletter, report of the president and treasurer, and miscellany
    - Bohemian Club - Supervisors Camp, 1981-1984 (Folder 210: 7-10)
      Brochures, correspondence, form letters, memoranda, note, report, roster of members, officers, and committees, statement of revenues and expenses, and miscellany. Includes one photographic print depicting a number of individuals, undated
    - Cleveland Conference in Chicago, 1985 December 6-7 (Folder 211: 1)
      Final itinerary, list of letters to be mailed, membership list, memoranda, newsletter, and notes
    - Cosmos Club, 1982-1985 (Folder 211: 2-3)
      Annual report, bulletin, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter
    - Castilleja School - Board minutes
      - 1981 January - Current (Folder 211: 4)
        Memoranda and minutes of meetings of Board of Trustees
      - 1981-1983 (Folder 211: 5)
        Correspondence, disclosure statement, financial statement, memoranda, monthly gift report, pledge form, printed matter, report of Depreciation Reserve and Endowment Funds, and related materials
      - 1984-1985 (Folder 211: 6)
        Annual report, correspondence, endowments, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletter, supplement to catalogue, and miscellany
      - 1986 (Folder 211: 7)
        General correspondence. Includes list of endowments, memoranda, printed matter, and minutes of Board meetings
    - Fellowship Forum
      - 1977-1980 (Folder 212: 1)
        Article, biographical summary and questionnaire, clipping, notes, personal biography, printed matter, program analysis, and report
      - 1981 (Folder 212: 2)
        Includes clippings, correspondence, and printed matter
      - 1982 (Folder 212: 3)
        Biographical summary, calendar for program committee, clipping, and correspondence
      - 1983 (Folder 212: 4)
        Biographical summary and questionnaire, correspondence, list of possible speakers, and memoranda
      - 1984 (Folder 212: 5)
        Biographical summary and questionnaire, correspondence, and memoranda
    - Cosmos Club
      - 1981 (Folder 212: 6)
        Annual report, bulletin, correspondence, check list for submission of nominees, list of Stanford University Faculty members, memoranda, and proposal for membership
      - 1982-1984 (Folder 212: 7)
        Cosmos Club - Sponsored membership. Article, correspondence, memoranda, notes, printed matter, and related materials
  - Davis, Paul H. Correspondence
    - 1972-1977 (Folder 212: 8)
    - 1977-1981 (Folder 212: 9)
  - Organizations, 1977-1986
    - Government Research Council (GRC) of San Mateo County
      - 1980 (Folder 213: 1)
        Forest management, List of membership and minutes of South Skyline Association (SSA),
      - 1982 June - December (Folder 213: 2)
        Balance sheet of San Mateo County, correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meeting, and remarks
      - 1983 (Folder 213: 3)
        Balance sheet and cash flow statement, correspondence, form letter, minutes of meeting, list of members of San Mateo County, GRC monthly report and program committee report, and press release
      - 1984
        - January - June (Folder 213: 4)
          Arithmetic sheet, balance sheet, clippings, list of GRC officer, minutes of meetings, memoranda, message from the president, monthly report, note from Ronald Reagan, printed matter, and related materials
        - July - December (Folder 213: 5)
          Cash flow statement, correspondence, financial report, printed matter,public meeting, and study
      - 1985 (Folder 213: 6)
        Memoranda and minutes of meetings
    - Government Research Foundation, 1985 (Folder 213: 7)
      Minutes of executive committee meetings and related materials
    - Stanford Associates, 1981-1986 (Folder 214: 1)
      Certificate, correspondence, directory, form letter, list of officers, memoranda, and reports
    - Californians for Preservation Action, 1977-1982 (Folder 214: 2)
      Correspondence. Also includes newsletters and printed matter
    - Oregon's Historic Preservation League, 1977-1978 (Folder 214: 3)
      Newsletters
    - Stanford University School of Education, 1983-1986 (Folder 214: 4)
      Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and press release
  - Enloe, Cortez F. correspondence, 1977-1980 (Folder 214: 5)
  - Hoover Institution, 1977-1980 (Folder 214)
    - Endowed chair in education, 1977-1978 (Folder 214: 6)
      Clipping, letter, and remark
      - Hanna collection press materials
      - First press materials - News release
        - Drafts, 1977 (Folder 214: 7)
        - Campus Report, 1977 (Folder 214: 8)
        - Stanford University News Service, 1977 (Folder 214: 9)
        - Others, 1977-1978 (Folder 214: 10)
      - Second press materials - Article for educational journal
        - Planning the article, 1977 (Folder 214: 11)
          Includes memoranda
        - Drafts and final copy, 1977 and undated (Folder 214: 12)
          Includes memoranda and note
        - Correspondence with educational journals, 1977-1978 (Folder 214: 13)
      - Third press materials - Brochure and draft, 1977-1980 (Folder 214: 14)
        Includes correspondence and memoranda
  - Organizations, 1980-1984
    - Historic House Association of America (HHAA), 1982-1983 (Folder 215: 1-2)
      Brochures, clipping, correspondence, newsletters, and notes
    - The Japan Society, 1982-1984 (Folder 215: 3)
      Journals, memoranda, and miscellany
    - Peninsula Community Foundation (formerly The San Mateo Foundation), 1980-1983 (Folder 215: 4)
      Announcement, article, clipping, correspondence, financial data, list of members of community sponsors committee, newsletter, and miscellany
    - Society of American Archivists (SAA), 1981 (Folder 215: 5)
      Memoranda
  - Hamline University Correspondence, 1979-1984
    - 1979-1982 (Folder 215: 6)
      Commencement address by Paul R. Hanna, correspondence, memoranda, newsletter, and schedule for orientation of board members
    - 1983 (Folder 215: 7)
      Brochure, correspondence, flyers, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and miscellany
    - 1983 December 29 - 1984 May 4 (Folder 215: 8)
      Bulletin and correspondence
    - 1984 (Folder 215: 9)
      Brochure, clipping, correspondence, endowment report, flyer, memoranda, minutes of meeting, and printed matter
  - Stanford Magazine article, 1984 (Folder 215: 10)
    Correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter
- INCREMENT OF JUNE 1988
  - APPOINTMENT BOOKS, 1951/1987
    - 1951, 1953-54 (Box 216)
    - 1955-57 (Box 217)
    - 1971-73 (Box 218)
    - 1974-76 (Box 219)
    - 1977-79 (Box 220)
    - 1980-83 (Box 221)
    - 1983-85 (Box 222)
    - 1986-87 (Box 223)
    - Correspondence (Box 224-229A)
    - Organizational files
    - Forestry materials (Box 230-232)
    - Articles by P. Hanna (Box 233-234)
    - Miscellaneous
    - "Community Education in the Philippines" (16 mm film) (Film self film shelf)
    - President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities (Box 235)
    - "Establishment of Jacks chairs in the School of Education, Stanford University" (Tabe cabinet tabe cabinet)
- INCREMENT OF JULY 1988
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1977-1988
    - Chronological
      - 1977 (Box 236)
      - 1979
      - 1980
      - 1981
        - A-D
        - E-L (Box 237)
        - M-P
        - R-V
        - W-Z
      - 1982
        - A-E
        - F-H
        - I-M
        - N-S (Box 238)
        - T-Z
    - Alphabetical
      - Britton, Glen (Houghton Mifflin Co.), 1977-1982
      - Brooks, E. Howard, 1977-1987
      - Campbell, W. Glenn, 1977-1988
      - Dennis, Lawrence, 1988
      - Drachkovitch, Milorad, 1978-1983
      - Eitner, Lorenz, 1981-82
      - Elsen, Al, 1983
      - Hastorf, Albert, 1981-84
      - Hessen, Robert, 1978-1980
      - Hook, Sidney, 1987
      - Kennedy, Donald, 1981-87
      - Lassner, Franz, 1978-1982
      - Mosher, Paul, 1982-83
      - Nash, Robert, 1982-83
      - Nishiyama, Chiaki, 1978-1983
      - U.S. Department of Education, 1987
  - SUBJECT FILE, 1977-1988
    - Castilleja School
    - Conferences
      - Academy for Educational Development, April 1985
      - Arms Control Conference, September 1983
      - Atlantic Council, 1984 (Box 239)
      - Cleveland Conference
        - 1986
        - 1987
      - Higher Education in the U.S., October/November 1983
      - Institute for Research on Education Finance and Governance, October 1984
      - National Advisory Council on Educational Research and Improvement, March 1988
      - National Institute of Education, August 1985
      - Pacific Basin Conference, August 1983
      - Social Science Education Consortium, June 1986
    - Habib, Philip (Box 240)
    - Hung, Ernie
    - Stanford University, School of Education
      - Conference, November 17, 1981
      - Math Science Proposal, February 1985
      - Special Task Force on Development
- INCREMENT OF FEBRUARY 1988
  (accessioned April 1989)
  - Davis. O. L., "Harold Drummond and Social Education The Practitioner and the Practical," paper, November 15, 1987. (Box-folder 240: 1)
- Incremental Materials (Box 241-248)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu